<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<blog>
	<post>
		<date>April 19, 2022</date>
		<author>Charles Varga</author>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<summary><image_path>https://charleskvarga.com/author/charles-varga/avatar_hu2c18dd1917d470710f3bd4fcb5a65139_218642_150x150_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</image_path><text>
			The author of this blog site
		</text></summary>
		<body>My name is Charles Varga, and I am a Computer Science MS student at Pace University. I received my BS in Computer Science at the University of Maryland Baltimore County. Throughout my undergraduate career, I have worked alongside leaders from multiple levels of government, military, and academia to both provide cybersecurity services and gain experience in my field of specialty. I currently work as a cybersecurity analyst for the State of Florida, where I provide both security services and infrastructure support for the Department of Financial Services. My interests include red teaming, penetration testing, and malware analysis. My non-cybersecurity interests include running, biking, and stand-up paddleboarding. I have an existing personal site which serves as my blog. In addition to it being built on a completely different web framework, I also provide a tutorial on how to build one yourself with the same framework. You can access it at https://charleskvarga.com</body>
	</post>
	<post>
		<date>April 19, 2022</date>
		<author>Charles Varga</author>
		<title>Work and Study Post-pandemic</title>
		<summary><image_path>https://cdn10.bostonmagazine.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2020/03/working-from-home-tips-social.jpg</image_path><text>
			How remote work, return to office/campus, and other factors have influenced the future of work and study
		</text></summary>
		<body>As a student who has come to rely on online learning during the pandemic, I have experienced the impact of remote work and study first-hand. My old university made a sharp transition from exclusively in-person learning to almost completely online learning in the start of the pandemic...only to make a full 180 in the fall of 2021. Furthermore, I have completed two summer internships between 2020 and 2021-- one virtual and the other in-person. I now attend university remotely in New York City and work full-time in-person in Tallahassee, FL. Having said that, mastering online learning is as much a science as it is an art, and it seems to be one which is in decline. The current trend in both the workplace and the classroom is mostly along these lines: if you didn't operate remotely before the pandemic, expect to return to in-person operations soon. This is indeed exactly what is happening at most universities around the United States. This trend is also being picked up by employers. Reactions to these two parallel trends, however, seem to diverge from one another. Among employers, it is now common to lament over how RTO (return to office) has triggered a so-called "Great Resignation", where employees are quitting en-masse in search for greener pastures. RTO is a major contributor to this trend, so some employers are responding by extending WFH (work from home), offering it as a permanent benefit for some positions, or moving to a fully remote workforce in some cases. Among universities, however, it's...all quiet on their front. There is no "Great Dropout" or "Great Transfer" equivalent of the Great Resignation among universities, and although some institutions such as Pace briefly reintroduced exclusively online classes in January 2022 as a result of the Omnicron variant spread, academia's stance on RTC (return to campus) has been mostly steady post-pandemic. Moreover, the ongoing decline in post-secondary enrollment has virtually nothing to do with RTC. As a student who transferred out of his old university due to the elimination of online classes which were introduced during the pandemic, this surprises me quite a lot. For this reason, I decided to examine the circumstances which have allowed academia to suffer a more lenient if not non-punitive fate compared to their industrial counterparts. This is by no means an exhaustive list, but it is a means of informing the curious reader of current societal trends. Based on my findings, the trend which appears more in the headlines, the Great Resignation, is not occurring only because of RTO. Although many employees dread the thought of going back to long commutes, water-cooler talk, and office politics, most fully employed individuals are surprisingly very happy with their current jobs despite the eventuality of RTO. So what is to blame for this mass exodus of employees to new employers? Well, most people who are either currently leaving their employers or thinking about doing so are doing so for positive reasons, such as the desire for career advancement-- as opposed to negative reasons, such as being miserable at their current job. Imagine the following scenario: Pre-pandemic, you've always worked as an incident responder for your current employer-- effectively in the defensive side of cybersecurity-- but during the pandemic, you spent your extra free-time as a result of WFH learning how to master penetration testing and red-teaming-- both subdisciplines of the offensive side of cybersecurity. Your current employer, however, has never hired internally for pen-testing or red-teaming positions. For that reason, you've hit a career dead-end if you want to transition to offensive security at your current employer. Your only option is to quit and find employment elsewhere. This brings me to my final point: why hasn't enrollment in post-secondary institutions declined at an accelerated rate parallel to that of the Great Resignation? My theory is that those who enroll in post-secondary institutions are mostly already decided on what they want to study, and the curricula for most college degrees are broad enough to cover theory for most of the possible subdisciplines in each major. For that reason, there is generally no need for most students to drop out or transfer universities, unless a serious personal difference between them and the university they currently attend compels them to do so.
		</body>
	</post>
	<post>
		<date>April 23, 2022</date>
		<author>Charles Varga</author>
		<title>How to Create a Blog Site with ReactJS</title>
		<summary><image_path>https://www.techtodayinfo.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20200917_104446_0000.jpg</image_path><text>
			I created this site with ReactJS. Now, with this tutorial, you can too!
		</text></summary>
		<body>
			To start off, you need to download the latest versions of npm and npx, which will allow you to create a ReactJS app with a defualt template and subsequently host it from your local machine. Next, open up a Terminal and type the command "npm install -g create-react-app" to install the npx sub-command which allows you to create a React app from scratch. Once that gets installed, you need to run "npx create-react-app my-app", with the name of your app taking the place of "my-app" in that command. This command will create a directory named "my-app", into which you can cd. By now, you've already reached half of your goal. Whenever you want to test your React app and see what it looks like on a web browser, just type "npm start" from inside your app directory, then visit localhost:3000 on your web browser.

			Now we will focus on the part where you actually write the code that will make your blog possible. This blog post describes what you need to do at a high-level, but does not actually give you example code to work off of. The point of this post is to allow you sufficient flexibility to create your ReactJS blog in a manner that you want. You will need to start off by deciding on how you will want to store your blog posts. I, for example, store my blog posts in XML files. Some people may choose to work with a database and/or store it as JSON instead. Next, you will need to edit App.js, which is where you will be writing code that will render your page, along with the contents of your blog posts. Start off by familiarizing yourself with how templating works, because that is often what enables most web developers to use any web framework to create many pages of the same type without having to take up too much disk space on their servers. You will be templating out variables in your JavaScript in order to render your HTML properly. In the case of ReactJS, there is a render() function which allows you to input HTML text combined with any variables you defined in your JS code enclosed in curly braces {}. Furthermore, your app is built as a data structure, from which you will extract contents to print out to your web page. Utilize the following tutorial to understand how the React Component works when creating your data structure: https://reactjs.org/tutorial/tutorial.html Your data structure should contain variables that correspond to the typical contents of a blog post, such as title, author, date, and body. You will utulize the render() function to display each of these posts in a manner that the JS iterates through each post stored in your data structure and prints them out.
		</body>
	</post>
</blog>
